<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>

  <info>
    <name>Nouser's Items</name>
    <update version="0.3">
      <file name="nouseritems.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Nouser757/AuroraDand/main/Nousers-Misc/Items.xml" />
    </update>
  </info>

  <element name="Ring of Attunement" type="Magic Item" source="Nouser's Misc Homebrew" id="ID_NOUS_NOUS_MAGIC_ITEM_RING_OF_ATTUNEMENT">
		<description>
			<p>When you would attune to an item, you may instead attune it to this ring, ignoring all normal requirements for attunement.</p>
      <p>Only one item can be attuned to the ring, and whoever is wearing the ring is considered as being attuned to the item.</p>
			<br />
      <p>This item can hold up to 4 charges, as an action, you can expend a charge to teleport the item attuned to this ring to anywhere within a 5ft radius of it.</p>
      <p>This item regains 1d4 charges daily at dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Rings</set>
			<set name="type">Ring</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">ring</set>
			<set name="equippable">true</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

  <element name="Box of Accounting" type="Magic Item" source="Nouser's Misc Homebrew" id="ID_NOUS_NOUS_MAGIC_ITEM_BOX_OF_ACCOUNTING">
		<description>
			<p>This small handheld box can hold a seemingly unlimited amount of copper, silver, gold, and platinum pieces, but no other items.</p>
      <p>There are four buttons on the box, one of copper, one of silver, one of gold, and one of platinum.</p>
      <p>Pressing one of the buttons will transmute all pieces inside the box into an equivalent amount of the corresponding type of piece. (E.g. 10 gold pieces turns into 100 silver pieces)</p>
      <p>Anything that could not be cleanly converted into the corresponding type of piece will remain unchanged. (E.g. 97 silver pieces turns into 9 gold pieces, 7 silver pieces)</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="equippable">false</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Key of Mimicry" type="Magic Item" source="Nouser's Misc Homebrew" id="ID_NOUS_NOUS_MAGIC_ITEM_KEY_OF_MIMICRY">
		<description>
			<p>A small key, decorated with teeth, that can unlock any non-magical lock.</p>
			<p>However, whenever this key is used to unlock something, you must make an Arcana check and consult the following table: </p>
			<table>
				<thread>
					<tr><td>Result</td><td>Effect</td></tr>
				</thread>
				<tr><td>1 or less</td><td>Unlocked object, and this key, turn into hostile mimics.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2-9</td><td>Unlocked object turns into a hostile mimic.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>10-19</td><td>Object is unlocked with no other effect.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>20 or more</td><td>Unlocked object turns into a mimic that can understand (but not speak) Common, and follows any commands that the person attuned to this key gives it.</td></tr>
			</table>
			<br />
			<p>Mimics created by this effect cannot be healed, or transform in any way.</p>
			<p>Upon death, a mimic created by this effect turns back in the original object, in the same state and position it was in after being unlocked, but before being transformed.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type" addition="Key">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="equippable">false</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ashen Tattoo" type="Magic Item" source="Nouser's Misc Homebrew" id="ID_NOUSE_NOUSE_MAGIC_ITEM_ASHEN_TATTOO">
		<description>
			<p>Produced by a special needle, this magic tattoo features firey imagery, and uses ink that glows brightly.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Tattoo Attunement.</em></strong> To attune to this item, you hold the needle to your skin where you want the tattoo to appear, pressing the needle there throughout the attunement process. When the attunement is complete, the needle turns into the ink that becomes the tattoo, which appears on the skin.</p>
			<p class="indent">If your attunement to the tattoo ends, the tattoo vanishes, and the needle reappears in your space.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Rebirth.</em></strong> One hour after the death of the wearer, if they are still dead, they will be magically revived at their current location, with max HP and 1 exhaustion, all other resources are in the same state they were in just before death.
Upon revival, the wearer will revive with a scar based on how they died, the severity of the scar is based on how many times the wearer has been revived with this tattoo.</p>
			<table>
				<thread>
					<tr><td>Revival</td><td>Scar</td></tr>
				</thread>
				<tr><td>First</td><td>Small scar (e.g. a healed cut around the neck, or singed hair)</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Second</td><td>Medium scar (e.g. a limp, or a damaged eye)</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Third</td><td>Large scar (e.g. a missing limb, or being unable to walk)</td></tr>
			<p>A scar inflicted by this tattoo can only be healed using Greater Restoration, or Wish
With every revival the tattoo either shrinks a little or glows less, and after the third revival it entirely disappears. Any scars inflicted remain.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Curse.</em></strong> This tattoo can only be removed with a Remove Curse spell (if the wearer is willing), and is entirely destroyed once removed. Any scars inflicted remain.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">tattoo, revive, death</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Tattoo</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="charges">3</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
</elements>
  